American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIi. 1897 APS.Archives.IIi APS.Archives.IIi
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 8, 1897; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns request of A.S. Barnes & co. to use Wilder's illustrations for paper on the brain of a cat. Letter pasted to Barnes letter, Jan. 30, 1897.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Feb. 8, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Wundt, Wilhelm Max, 1832-1920
    Leipzig, A.L.S. 2p. In German Acknowledges receipt of diploma.
  - Letter to Frank Hamilton Cushing, Feb. 8, [1897]; 11x8-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Copy. Please send his MS. on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 9, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Denison scientific association, Granville, Ohio
    Granville, O., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Requests publications.
  - Receipt to I[saac] Minis Hays for cash, Feb. 9, 1897; 9x6; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 10, 1897; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerns illustrations for paper, "New Paleozoic vertebrata from Illinois, Ohio, and Pennsylvania." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 71-91.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 10, 1897; 13-1/4x8-1/4; New South Wales. Dept. of Mines and Agriculture
    Sydney, Typed L. 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 10, 1897; 8x5; Nuttall, Zelia, 1858-1933
    Lausanne, A.L.S. 3p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to F[rederick] Prime, Feb. 10, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; G.E. Stechert & Co.
    New York, Printed L. filled in in MS. on postal card 1p. and add. Order for publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], Feb. 10, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Suggests calendar of Franklin correspondence.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 10, Dec. 10, 1897; G.E. Stechert & Co.
    New York, L. 22 items, 15 of them on postal cards Various sizes Orders for publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 11, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns letter from A.E. Brown. Reappoints standing committee on premiums.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 11, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Mason, William Pitt, 1853-1937
    Troy, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society;], Feb. 11, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Montegazza, Paolo, 1831?-1910
    Florence, A.L.S. 1p., end. Acknowledges receipt of diploma.
  - Letter to [Antonio] de Gregorio, Feb. 12, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. In French Copy Asks for more information about MS. he asks to submit.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 12, 1897; 9-1/4x6, 7x4-1/2; J. B. Lippincott Company
    Phila., L. 1p. 2p. printed sheet pasted to letter Quotes price for Murray's English Dic-tionary.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic], Feb. 13, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Murphy's, William F., sons
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Encs. wanting Sends proof and sample paper.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Feb. 15, 1897; 9X5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. with Hays' reply, and end. Concerns papers by Cushing and Mercer.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 15, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Geological and Natural History Survey of Minnesota
    Minneapolis, Printed L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Latest part of Final Report is ready.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, Feb. 16, 1897; 8x5; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Will send off what MS. he has ready, of his paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to Edwin Grant Conklin, Feb. 19, 1897; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: I[saac] Minis Hays. 1p. Announces his election to membership.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, Feb. 19, 1897; 8x5; Hitchcock, Charles H. (Charles Henry), 1836-1919
    Hanover, N.H., A.L.S. 2p. Submits proposal for geological map of North America.
  - Letter to C[harles] H[enry] Hitchcock, Feb. 20, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L. 1p. Copy Concerns cost of proposed geological map of North America.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, Feb. 20, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Free Library of Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Concerns unmarked package from London.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 20, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Geological Survey (U.S.)
    Washington, Typed L.S.: H. C. Rizer 1p., end. by C[harles] C. D[arwin] Bulletin No. 127.
  - Letter to Frederick Prime, Feb. 20, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. by Prime to Hays Offers books for library.
  - Report as to the Cabinet, Feb. 22, 1897; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Philadelphia] Typed D.S.: Henry Pettit, J. Cheston Morris, Benj. Smith Lyman. 13p. with MS corrections. (see APS. Curator' s reports.)
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, Feb. 22, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Hitchcock, Charles H. (Charles Henry), 1836-1919
    Hanover, N.H., A.L.S. 3p. Concerns estimate of cost for proposed geological map of North America.
  - Letter to J. Hayes [sic], Feb. 23, 1897; 11x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns Library Committee.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 23, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Preston, H. W.
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 1p. Orders copy of Pursh's Journal.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 23, 1897; 5-1/4x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Returns books.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 24, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Budge, E. A. Wallis (Ernest Alfred Wallis), Sir, 1857-1934
    [London], A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges receipt of certificate of membership.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 26, 1897; 11-1/4X8-3/4; Levytype Co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Encs. wanting Sends paper samples for plates for Mercer's paper on the sloth. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 36-70.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 26, 1897; 8x5; Preston, H. W.
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns publication of Pursh's journal.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 27, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Baur, Georg, 1859-1898
    Chicago, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of Ortmann's paper on natural selection and separation. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 175-192.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 27, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Withdraws paper. Refers to F. Prime.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Feb. 28, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Goodspeed, Arthur W. (Arthur Willis), b. 1860
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his part in coming symposium and talk on radiographs. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, p.142.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, Feb., 1897; 8x5; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    [Washington], Monday, A.L.S. 1p. Concerns bill for illustrations for his paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, March 1, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns papers under consideration. Refers to Scudder. Mentions Grote's tendency to sneer at rivals. Will sign diplomas.
  - Letter to J. Minis Hayes [sic], March 3, 1897; 6-1/2x8; Dougherty, William R.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Estimate on carpentry wor for library.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, March 5, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Bache, Richard Meade
    A.L.S. 2p. Will ask P. Frazer to second nomination of Dr. Baker.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 5, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Cannot attend meeting. Returns proof of Peckham's papers on petroleum. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 103-112.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], March 5, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns his proposed calendar of the Franklin correspondence.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic; Phila.], March 6, 1897; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    A.L.S. 3p. Has come to Phila. to work without interruption on his paper on excavations in Florida. Refers to Frazer. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 6, 1897; 11-1/4x8-3/4; Ebers, Georg, 1837-1898
    Munich, A.L.S. 1p., end. In German. Acknowledges receipt of diploma.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 6, 1897; 9x5-3/4; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., A.L.S.: W[illiam] A. Pickell, Sec'y. 4p. Explains bill in question.
  - Letter to [James Cheston] Morris, March 8, 1897; 9x6; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Cannot second nomination of a Dr. Baker as he does not know him. Will support nomination of E.R. Squibb. Refers to R.M. Bache.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, March 8, 1897; 6-3/4x9; Furness, William Henry, 1866-1920
    Wallingford, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper.
  - Letter to J[sic] Minis Hays, March 8, 1897; 11x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns meeting of Library Committee.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 8, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Ketcham's, B., Sons
    Phila., L. 1p. Estimate for carpentry work.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 8, 1897; 9x8; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L.S.: W[illiam] A. Pickell. 1p. Sends copy for examination.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 8, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; New York Public Library
    New York, Typed L.S.: John S[haw] Billings 2p. Advises on classification and cataloguing of serials.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 8, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Returns proofs of papers on petroleum.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 8, 1897; 10x8; Geological Survey (U.S.)
    Washington, Typed L.S.: G[rove] K[arl] Gilbert 1p., end. Encs. wanting Recommends the Catalogue des bibliographies géologiques.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 9, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Mabery, Charles Frederic, 1850-
    A.L. on postal card 1p. and add. Gives address.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, March 9, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Recommends Drexel graduates for work in library.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], March 9, 1897; 8x5; Tucker, Henry St. George, 1853-1932
    Lexington, Va., A.L.S. 1p. Announces death of J.R. Tucker.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 9, 1897; 11x8-1/2; White, James T. & Company
    New York, Typed L. 1p., end. Asks for autograph of Gerhard Troost to include in National Cyclopedia of American Biography.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 9, [1897]; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, [Pa.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Has received proofs.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, March 10, 1897; 8x10-1/2; Goodspeed, Arthur W. (Arthur Willis), b. 1860
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will try to write something for him soon.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 10, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Société royale de géographie d'Anvers
    Antwerp, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Edm. Lombaerts 2p., end. Concerns missing Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 10, [1897]; 10x8; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns proofs.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 11, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Indiana Engineering Society
    Cloverdale, Ind., A.L.S.: J. F. O'Brien 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, March 11, 1897; 11x8; Kennelly, Arthur E. (Arthur Edwin), 1861-1939
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns proofs of paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 11, 1897; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Neumann bros.
    New York, L. 1p., end. Orders Proceedings for H.f. Osborn.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], March 11, 1897; 8x5; Wright, Joseph, 1855-1930
    A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for subscription to English Dialect Dictionary.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 12, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; New York Public Library
    New York, Typed L.S.: J[ohn] S[haw] Billings 2p. Concerns classification of scientific periodicals.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], March 12, 1897; 11x8-1/2, 4-1/2x7; Vandiver, John L.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Enc. 1p.memorandum Concerns removal of education material from Free List by Ways and Means Committee. Enclosed is copy in Hays' hand of resolution on subject presented to A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Samuel Phillip] Sadtler, March 13, 1897; 8-1/2x7-1/2; Mabery, Charles Frederic, 1850-
    Cleveland, O., Typed L.S. with MS. corrections 1p. Concerns mailing of their papers on petroleum. For printed papers, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 126-136, 93-102.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 13, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Returns proofs. Arranges for separates.
  - Announcement of meeting, [March 13, 1897]; American Philosophical Society.
    1 postcard.
  - Letter to William Pepper, March 15, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Geikie, Archibald, Sir, 1835-1924
    London, A.L.S. 2p. Will attend meeting on May 7.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, March 16, 1897; 8x5; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    A.L.S. 3p. Enc. wanting Sends bill for preparing the illustrations for his paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], March 16, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Historical and Scientific Society of Manitoba
    Duluth, Minn., T.L.S.: L. A. Faulkner 1p. Asks for publications.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, March 16, 1897; 11x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Houston and Kennelly 1p. Concerns their paper on insulated conductors. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 144-175.
  - Letter to [James Cheston] Morris, March 16, 1897; 9x6; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Needs catalogue of Peale Stone Age collection to use in arranging collection. Will present copy to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 16, 1897; 6x4-1/2; Smyth, Albert Henry, 1863-1907
    Radnor, Pa., A.L.S. 3p. Holiday leave for employee. Death of George Stuart.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 16, 1897; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Stuart, Otis K.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Announces death of George Stuart.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 17, 1897; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns holiday leave for library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 18, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Sanderson, John H., & bro.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Estimate on magazine rack for library.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, March 19, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Day, David T. (David Talbot), 1859-1925
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Will return proofs of his paper on petroleum. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 112-115.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, March 19, 1897; 10-1/2x8; United States. Dept. of Agriculture
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Frederick V[ernon] Coville 1p. Concerns Contributions issued by the Botany Division.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 20, 1897; 6x4; Cruice, Mary Z.
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment as assistant in the library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 20, 1897; 10-3/4x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Harrisburg, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges A.P.S. endorsement of bill to create State Forestry Reservations.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 22, 1897; 10x8; McBratney, William C.
    Great Falls, Mont., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copies of Hilprecht's papers on Babylonian inscriptions. For printed papers, see: APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 5-54, 221-282.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, March 23, 1897; 6x4; Cruice, Mary Z.
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Concerns Appointment as assistant in the library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 23, 1897; 6-1/4x4; Frazier, Benjamin W. (Benjamin West)
    South Bethlehem, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 23, 1897; 7x5-1/2; Magie, William Francis, 1858-1943
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 24, 1897; 8x5; Bastin, Edson S. (Edson Sewell), 1843-1897
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, March 25, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Day, David T. (David Talbot), 1859-1925
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on the origin of petroleum, givenat symposium on subject. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 112-115.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 26, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Thompson, Edward Maunde, Sir, 1840-1929
    London, A.L.S. 4p. Exchange of publications with British Museum.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 27, 1897; 8x4-3/4; Lewis, George Albert, 1829-1915
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, March 28, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Blake, William P. (William Phipps), 1826-1910
    Tucson, Ariz., A.L.S. 1p. Change of address.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 29, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/2; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L.S.: W[illiam] A. Pickell, with MS. addition. 1p., end. Gives weight and postage of issues of Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 29, 1897; 10x8-1/2; Winand, Paul A. N.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends copy of his remarks on Houston and Kennelly paper. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 170-173.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, March 30, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Cross, M. H. (Michael Hurley), 1833-1897
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 3p. and end. Announces death of William Blasius.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], March 30, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; The Electrician
    London, Typed L. 1p., end. Asks for notices of papers on electrical subjects.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 30, 1897; 11x8-1/2; W.H. Lowdermilk & Co.
    Washington, L. 1p. Enc. wanting. Returns bill.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 30, 1897; 10-1/4x8; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Suggests regulations for library.
  - Letter to [James Cheston Morris], March 30, [1897?]; 8X5; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Asks location of catalogue of Peale Stone Age collection. Refers to F. Fraley, E. Morison.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 31, 1897; 8x5; Pennsylvania. Commission to collect and print the Statutes at Large
    A.L.S.: James T[yndale] Mitchell 4p. Asks to use MS. volume of Pennsylvania laws.
  - Letter to the Instituto Medico Nacional, Mexico, April 1, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. In French Copy Corrects address. Refers to death of Phillips.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, April 1, [1897]; 11x8-1/2; W.H. Lowdermilk & Co.
    Washington, Typed L. 1p., end. Concerns a payment. Refers to Horn.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, April 1, 1897; Blasius, Oscar
  - Remarks upon the Report of Curators as to the Cabinet, April 2, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pettit, Henry, 1842-1921
    A.MS. with corrections 7p. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns renovation of North Room of Hall. Cf. Proceedings, v.36, p.175.
  - Letter to William Pepper, April 3, 1897; 8x5; Phelps, Edward John, 1822-1900
    New Haven, Conn., Typed L.S. 4p. Cannot participate in discussion on Edmunds' paper on international arbitration. Gives views against such arbitration. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 320-323.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], April 4, 1897; 10-1/4x8-1/4; Berlese, Antonio, 1863-1927
    Portici, [Italy] L.S. 2p. In Italian Asks to exchange with the Rivista di patologia vegetale. English translation enclosed.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, April 6, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Cock, George B.
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Enc. Wanting Sends transcript of symposium on petroleum.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 6, 1897; 10x8; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Copy Refuses to serve on committee for the disposal of the geological collection. Angry letter.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 7, 1897; 9-1/2x6; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Samuel G[ibston] Dixon 1p., end. Academy will take Lewis and Clark and Muhlenberg plant collections.
  - Letter to F [sic] Frazer, April 7, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Instituto Médico Nacional (Mexico)
    Mexico [City] L.S.: F[ernando] Altamira 1p., end. In Spanish Exchange of publications. Refers to Phillips.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 7, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting Concerns circulars for Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 7-Dec. 27, 1897; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., L. 8 items 10p., end. Various sizes Printing of papers. Refers to Cope, Mercer, F.C. Phillips, Cushing, Hilprecht, Drake.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 7, [1897?]; 7x5-1/2; Wister, Owen, 1860-1938
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Cannot prepare paper now. Refers to Furness.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, April 8, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Cock, George B.
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his stenographic transcript of the symposium on petroleum.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 8, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1803-1901
    [Phila.], L.S. 2p. Concerns obituary of Hartshorne by J.C. Morris, H.D. Gregory by C.R. Gregory, G. Stuart by A.H. Smyth.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, April 8, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Payson, L. E. (Lewis Edwin), 1840-1909
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of papers on petroleum.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 11, 1897; University of Oxford.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 12, 1897; 10x8; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Samuel G. Dixon, Edw[ard] J. Nolan, Benj[amin] Tharp. 1p., end. Asks support for amendment to rules of International Postal Congress.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 12, 1897; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. About William Blasius.
  - Report recommending deposit of A.P.S. botanical collections (herbaria) at Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, April 13, 1897; 8x5; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    A.D. with MS. corrections. S.: Benj[amin] Smith Lyman, J[ames] Cheston Morris 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Cf. Proceedings, v.36, p.216.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 13, 1897; 11x8-1/2; New Hampshire State Library
    Concord, N.H., Typed L.S.: Arthur H. Chase 1p., end. Asks for Proceedings lacking in its set.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 13, 1897; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Platt, Franklin, 1844-1900
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Declines to serve on committee to dispose of APS geological specimens.